export const quizData = {
  "chapter1/lesson1": [
    {
      id: 1,
      type: "choice",
      order: 1,
      question: "What are the sparks that Benjamin Franklin saw?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Electricity", "Power of God", "Fire", "Thor"],
      answer: "Electricity",
      explanation:
        "When Franklin flew his kite in a storm, he saw sparks caused by electricity from lightning. It proved that lightning and electricity are the same!",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What is electricity made of?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Moving electrons", "Moving air", "Light Energy", "Heat"],
      answer: "Moving electrons",
      explanation:
        "Electricity is the flow of charges carried by electrons. When they move, they create an electric current!",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Which object can store electricity for later use?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Battery", "Wire", "Light bulb", "Switch"],
      answer: "Battery",
      explanation:
        "A battery stores electrical energy. When connected to a circuit, it lets electricity flow out and power things!",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What does electricity need to flow through?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Metal", "Wool", "Plastic", "Paper"],
      answer: "Metal",
      explanation:
        "Electricity travels best through conductors like metal. That’s why wires are usually made of copper!",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      type: "match",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Meaning of Electronics",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        { term: "Electron", definition: "Moves to create electricity" },
        { term: "Battery", definition: "Stores electrical energy" },
        { term: "Conductor", definition: "Let electricity flow easily" },
        { term: "Insulator", definition: "Blocks the flow of electricity" },
      ],
      explanation: "",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      type: "match",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Atom & Charge",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        { term: "Proton", definition: "Positive charge in an atom" },
        { term: "Electron", definition: "Negative charge that moves" },
        { term: "Neutron", definition: "Neutral charge" },
        { term: "Nucleus", definition: "Center of the atom" },
      ],
      explanation: "",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What are the sparks that Benjamin Franklin saw?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Electricity", "Election", "Elevator", "Elon Musk"],
      answer: "Electricity",
      explanation:
        "When Franklin flew his kite in a storm, he saw sparks caused by electricity from lightning. It proved that lightning and electricity are the same!",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What is electricity made of?",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        "Moving electrons",
        "Battery",
        "Power of God",
        "Moving protons",
      ],
      answer: "Moving electrons",
      explanation:
        "Electricity is the flow of charges carried by electrons. When they move, they create an electric current!",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      type: "fill",
      order: NaN,
      question:
        "The _ is the part of the atom that moves to create electricity.",
      image: "-",
      options: ["neutron", "nucleus", "electron", "proton", "particle", "charge"],
      answer: "electron",
      explanation:
        "Electrons are the tiny, negatively charged particles zipping around atoms — they’re the ones that flow and create electricity!",
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      type: "fill",
      order: NaN,
      question: "A material that blocks electricity is called an _.",
      image: "-",
      options: ["engine", "insulator", "conductor", "electron", "battery", "metal"],
      answer: "insulator",
      explanation:
        "Insulators, like rubber or plastic, stop electricity from passing through — they keep circuits safe and controlled!",
    },
  ],
  "chapter1/lesson2": [
    {
      id: 1,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What is electric current?",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        "The flow of electric charge ",
        "The brightness of a light",
        "The size of a battery",
        "A type of lightning",
      ],
      answer: "The flow of electric charge ",
      explanation:
        "Electric current is simply how many electric charges are moving through a wire every second!",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What unit is used to measure current?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Ampere", "Ohm", "Volt", "Watt"],
      answer: "Ampere",
      explanation:
        "Electric current is measured in Amperes (or Amps). It tells us how strong the flow of electricity is.",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Which direction does current flow in a circuit?",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        "From positive to negative",
        "From negative to positive ",
        "From east to south",
        "From kanye to west",
      ],
      answer: "From positive to negative",
      explanation:
        'Even though electrons move from negative to positive, we say current flows from positive to negative — it’s called "conventional current."',
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What causes an electric current to flow?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Heat", "Magic", "Voltage", "Water"],
      answer: "Voltage",
      explanation:
        "Voltage is like the pressure that pushes electric charges through a wire. No Voltage = No Current!",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      type: "match",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Meaning of Current",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        { term: "Current", definition: "Flow of electric charge" },
        { term: "Voltage", definition: "Push that drives current" },
        { term: "Ampere", definition: "Unit used to measure current" },
        {
          term: "Electron",
          definition: "Particle that carries electric charge",
        },
      ],
      explanation: "",
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      type: "match",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Meaning of Circuit",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        {
          term: "Conventional current",
          definition: "Flows from positive to negative",
        },
        {
          term: "Electron flow",
          definition: "Real movement of electrons, negative to positive",
        },
        {
          term: "Closed circuit",
          definition: "A complete path for current to flow",
        },
        {
          term: "Open circuit",
          definition: "A path with a gap where current can't flow",
        },
      ],
      explanation: "",
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      type: "fill",
      order: NaN,
      question:
        "Electric current is the flow of _.",
      image: "-",
      options: ["energy", "protons", "heat", "electric charge", "current"],
      answer: "electric charge",
      explanation:
        "Electric current is like traffic — but instead of cars, it’s electric charge moving through the wires!",
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      type: "fill",
      order: NaN,
      question: "In wires, electricity usually flows because of moving _.",
      image: "-",
      options: ["atoms", "light", "electrons", "magnets", "copper", "metal"],
      answer: "electrons",
      explanation:
        "Electrons are the little travelers in metal wires — when they move, that’s electricity in action!",
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Which direction does current flow in a circuit?",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        "From positive to negative",
        "From negative to positive ",
        "In all directions",
        "Around the world"
      ],
      answer: "From positive to negative",
      explanation:
        'Even though electrons move from negative to positive, we say current flows from positive to negative — it’s called "conventional current."',
    },
  ],
  "chapter1/lesson3": [
    {
      id: 1,
      type: "match",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Meaning of Electronics",
      image: "-",
      options: [
        {
          term: "Resistor",
          definition: "Controls how much current flows",
        },
        {
          term: "LED",
          definition: "Lights up when current flows",
        },
        {
          term: "Battery",
          definition: "Supplies voltage to the circuit",
        },
        {
          term: "Switch",
          definition: "Opens or closes the path for the current",
        },
      ],
      explanation: "",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What are Light Emitting Diodes?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Switch", "Batery", "LED", "John"],
      answer: "LED",
      explanation:
        "LEDs are special components that glow when electricity flows through them — they're tiny lights used in everything from TVs to flashlights!",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "What does a resistor do in a circuit?",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Makes the circuit faster", "Increases current", "Stores electricity", "Slow down the flow of current"],
      answer: "Slow down the flow of current",
      explanation:
        "A resistor slows down the electric current — it’s like a traffic sign for electricity, keeping it from rushing too fast!",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      type: "choice",
      order: NaN,
      question: "Would the more Voltage = more Current",
      image: "-",
      options: ["Yes", "No"],
      answer: "Yes",
      explanation:
        "More voltage means more \"push\" for the electric charges, so yes — usually, higher voltage leads to more current (if resistance stays the same)!",
    },
  ]
};
